Guide to the DePitts / Smith / Ewing papers, 1934-1997 MS 1026
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
DePitts / Smith / Ewing papers
1934-1997
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
DePitts, Katherine E.
MS 1026
0.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
This collection contains Rice-related correspondence to Anne Marie Smith, photographs, ephemera, and a digitized poster.
Biographical / Historical
Anne Marie Smith received her BA from Rice Institute in 1938, as well as a Masters of Arts in 1940. She studied with Floyd S. Lear, with whom she maintained contact. She later married and took the name Ewing.
James DePitts graduated from Rice University in 1969. He has stayed connected to the music scene in Houston and has played in a Zydeco band named Grand Texas with Steve Bing.
Content Description
This collection contains Rice-related correspondence to Anne Marie Smith, photographs, ephemera, and a digitized poster. Letters in the collection discuss integration at Rice University.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Katherine E. DePitts, Dr. Anne, Rassios, and James DePitts in 2020.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Places
Rice University
Subjects (Persons)
DePitts, Katherine E.
- Series I: Anne Marie Smith / Anne Marie Ewing
  - Booklets and programs, 1934-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lear, Floyd S. correspondence, 1959; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rice-related correspondence, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: James DePitts
  - Beiersdorf, Herman aka Mickey Swift, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Steve Kane art/sign for Museum District Day on cardboard, 1997